Guide to the Evarts Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- William Maxwell Evarts, 1830-1901; Series II; 14.75 linear feet (36 boxes)
  - Memorabilia
    - Yale memorabilia, memorial tributes, and reminiscences
      - Memorial tributes to (Box 39, Folder 705)
      - Benjamin Robbins Curtis, 1874 (Box 39, Folder 705)
      - Samuel B. Ruggles, 1881 (Box 39, Folder 705)
      - Joseph S. Bosworth, 1884 (Box 39, Folder 705)
      - Memorial tributes: Peabody Education Fund to William Maxwell Evarts, William Wirt Henry, President William McKinley, and Bishop Henry B. Whipple, 1901 November 7 (Box 39, Folder 706)
      - Recollections of William Maxwell Evarts by Caspar F. Goodrich (Rear Admiral, United States Navy), undated (Box 39, Folder 707)
    - Miscellany
      - Wager between William Maxwell Evarts and H. W. Greenough, 1839 March 20 (Box 39, Folder 708)
      - New York State Constitutional Convention, diagram of chamber and seating of delegates, 1867 (Box 39, Folder 709)
      - "Peabody Education Fund, Proceedings of the Trustees at their Annual Meeting, New York", 1879 October 1 (Box 39, Folder 710)
      - Foreign legations in the United States, list of staff members and their addresses, 1880 December 28 (Box 39, Folder 711)
      - Complimentary railroad passes, menus, souvenirs of Paris (1881), silhouette of William Maxwell Evarts (Box 39, Folder 712)
      - "The Greater Evarts," by Leonard Woolsey Bacon, The Sunday School Times, vol. 43, no. 13, 1901 March 30 (Box 39, Folder 713)
      - Clippings (Box 39, Folder 714)
      - List of books (in the Evarts library, c. 1860?) (Box 39, Folder 715)
      - Maps and charts (Box 39, Folder 716)
  - Financial Records
    - Accounts, 1871-1900 (Box 40, Folder 717)
    - Account of George B. Elkins (deeds, agreements and receipts in re: his indebtedness to William Maxwell Evarts), 1849-1883 (Box 40, Folder 718)
    - Account with S. G. and G. C. Ward, Baring Brothers and Company, 1851-1857 1872-1886 (Box 40, Folder 719-720)
    - Account with Leather Manufacturers National Bank, 1867-1869 (Box 40, Folder 721)
    - Account with Ascutney National Bank, 1872-1876 (Box 40, Folder 722)
    - Account of Rachel Sherman, 1881 (Box 40, Folder 723)
    - Bills and receipts, 1844-1870 (Box 40, Folder 724)
    - Bills and receipts, United States, 1871 (Box 40, Folder 725)
    - Bills and receipts, Europe, 1871 (Box 40, Folder 726)
    - Bills and receipts, United States, 1872 (Box 40, Folder 727)
    - Bills and receipts, Europe, including records of expenses, 1872 (Box 40, Folder 728)
    - Bills and receipts, 1873-1877 (Box 40, Folder 729-733)
    - Bills and receipts, 1878-1901, undated (Box 41, Folder 734-742)
    - Bonds, receipts and memoranda, 1844-1884 (Box 41, Folder 743)
    - Bonds, record book, titled "F. G. King, October 21, 1901" (Box 41, Folder 744)
    - Insurance policies and receipts, 1850-1890 (Box 41, Folder 745)
    - Property tax receipts, 1845-1889 (Box 41, Folder 746-748)
    - Cancelled checks, 1862-1871 (Box 42, Folder 749-753)
    - Cancelled checks, 1875-1881 (Box 43, Folder 754-757)
- Evarts Family, 1753-(1800-1930)-1960; Series III; 2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  This series has three sub-sections:
  1) correspondence
  2) memorabilia
  3) legal and financial papers
  Correspondence contains letters to and from members of the Evarts family (excluding Jeremiah and William Maxwell Evarts). The letters are arranged chronologically.
  Memorabilia contains two copies of the Evarts, Genealogy, followed by articles, notes, verses, photographs, printed matter, recipes, and school lessons which belonged to various family members. There is one box of material, arranged chronologically.
  There is one box of legal and financial papers, arranged by type.
  - Correspondence
    - 1800-1805 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - 1806-1815 (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - 1816-1822 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - 1823-1824 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - 1825 (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - 1826 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - 1827 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - 1828 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - 1829 (Box 44, Folder 9-10)
    - 1830 (Box 44, Folder 12-12)
    - 1831 (Box 44, Folder 13-14)
    - 1832 (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - 1833 (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - 1834-1835 (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - 1836-1839 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - 1840-1844 (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - 1845-1849 (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - 1850-1859 (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - 1860-1862 (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - 1863 (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - 1864 (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - 1865-1869 (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - 1870-1877 (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - 1878 (Box 45, Folder 27-29)
    - 1879 (Box 45, Folder 30-33)
    - 1880 (Box 46, Folder 34-36)
    - 1881 (Box 46, Folder 37-39)
    - 1882 (Box 46, Folder 40)
    - 1883-1886 (Box 46, Folder 41)
    - 1887 (Box 46, Folder 34-47)
    - 1888-1889 (Box 46, Folder 43-44)
    - 1890-1897 (Box 46, Folder 45)
    - 1898 (Box 46, Folder 46)
    - 1899 (Box 46, Folder 47)
    - 1900 (Box 47, Folder 48-49)
    - 1901 (Box 47, Folder 50-51)
    - 1902 (Box 47, Folder 52)
    - 1903 (Box 47, Folder 53)
    - 1904-1909 (Box 47, Folder 54)
    - 1910-1914 (Box 47, Folder 55)
    - 1915-1919 (Box 47, Folder 56)
    - 1920 (Box 47, Folder 57-58)
    - 1921 (Box 47, Folder 59-60)
    - 1922-1928, 1956 (Box 47, Folder 61)
    - undated (Box 47, Folder 62-64)
  - Memorabilia
    - Evarts Genealogy (copy 1) (Box 48, Folder 65)
    - Evarts Genealogy (copy 2) (Box 48, Folder 66)
    - Evarts Genealogy, selected entries (Box 48, Folder 67)
    - Windsor, Vermont, publications: hymnbook; ordination sermon by A. A. Livermore; discourse on the death of William Henry Harrison by Charles B. Haddock; The Constitution of the Christian Church, by W. D. Wilson; and the Annual Report of the Vermont Domestic Missionary Society, 1836, 1838, 1841, 1843, 1859 (Box 48, Folder 68)
    - Printed matter (bulletins, advertizements, reports), 1841-1960, undated (Box 48, Folder 69)
    - Verses and memoranda, 1861, 1878, 1895, undated (Box 48, Folder 70)
    - Travel journal (fragment), describing Cumberland, Mount Savage, and Frostburg, Maryland (foundry and mines), by Charles Butler Evarts, 1867 July (Box 48, Folder 71)
    - Notes and printed matter (principally of Mary Evarts), 1870-1920, undated (Box 48, Folder 72)
    - Articles, authors unknown (Box 48, Folder 73)
      - "Scientific Colloquy," ms., undated (Box 48, Folder 73)
      - Remarks on summer vacations, ms., 1880 July 20 (Box 48, Folder 73)
      - "An Education in Funerals," typed ms., undated (Box 48, Folder 73)
    - Photographs, 1889, undated (Box 48, Folder 74)
    - Children's stories and a drawing, 1890, undated (Box 48, Folder 75)
    - Lessons of Elizabeth Lamson, 8th grade, 1894 (Box 48, Folder 76)
    - Recipes, undated (Box 48, Folder 77)
  - Legal and Financial Papers
    - Evarts family documents: deed, bond, and lease, 1753, 1758, 1812 (Box 49, Folder 78)
    - Barnes family documents: legal judgement (copy), Circa 1798 (Box 49, Folder 79)
    - Letter freeing a servant, written by Peter Livingston, undated (Box 49, Folder 79)
    - Certificates re: military service of Charles Butler Evarts and Roger Sherman Evarts, 1864-1868, 1920 (Box 49, Folder 80)
    - Financial papers, 1830-1950 (Box 49, Folder 81)
    - Windsor Estate - Accounts of joint tenants, 1909-1922, 1925-1927 (Box 49, Folder 82-84)
    - Federal Income Tax returns, 1916-1925 (Box 49, Folder 85-86)
    - Correspondence re: Federal Income Tax returns, 1917-1919 (Box 49, Folder 87)
    - Stocks, 1904, 1909, 1918 (Box 49, Folder 88)
    - Bonds, 1917-1918 (Box 49, Folder 88)
    - Insurance policies, 1924-1928, 1931 (Box 49, Folder 89)
    - Bills and receipts, 1881-1928, undated (Box 49, Folder 90-94)
    - Statements of account and cancelled checks, 1921 March-Apr, 1925 October-Nov, 1926 December-1927 June (Box 49, Folder 95)
    - Checkbook, 1926 November-1927 March (Box 49, Folder 95)
    - Statements of account and cancelled checks, 1927 June-December (Box 49, Folder 96)
  - Deeds, wills, and other legal papers of clients of William Maxwell Evarts (Box 49A)
  - Deeds, mortgages, leases, and contracts of William Maxwell Evarts (Box 49A)
  - Diplomas, certificates, appointments, principally of William Maxwell Evarts (Box 49B)
  - Account of a sea voyage from Boston to Savannah, Jeremiah Evarts to James Evarts, 1818 Jan (Box 49B)
  - Correspondence from William Maxwell Evarts to Ebenezer Rockwood Hoar, 1870-1871, 1885-1886 (Box 49B)
- Additional material, Accession 1978-M-002
  - Evarts, William Maxwell
    - Personal papers, 1848-1899, undated (Box 50, Folder 1-14)
    - Legal papers
      - General, 1847-1874 (Box 51, Folder 15-22)
      - General, 1874-1883, undated (Box 52, Folder 23-31)
      - Article, undated (Box 53, Folder 32)
      - Maitland peerage case, 1885 (Box 53, Folder 33-37)
      - Parish will case, 1832-1860, undated (Box 53, Folder 38-41)
      - Parish will case, 1857-1862, undated (Box 54, Folder 42-58)
      - President Johnson impeachment case, 1868 (Box 55, Folder 49-52)
    - Printed material, 1851-1881 (Box 55, Folder 53-57)
    - Printed material, 1882-1894, undated (Box 56, Folder 58-63)
  - Miscellanea
    - Finances (Box 57, Folder 64-65)
    - Legal notebooks (Box 57, Folder 66-68)
- Additional material, Accession 1982-M-012
  - Evarts, Jeremiah
    - Correspondence
      - Evarts, Mehetabel Sherman Barnes, 1810; 1818 (Box 58, Folder 69)
      - Miscellaneous, 1802; 1827-1831 (Box 58, Folder 70-71)
    - Diaries, 1796 - 1804 Feb, 1808 April - Jan, 1818 March - June (Box 58, Folder 72-76)
    - Essays, 1800 (Box 58, Folder 77)
    - Journal, 1831 (Box 58, Folder 78)
    - Poems, 1799-1800 (Box 58, Folder 79)
    - Pouch, 1821 (Box 58, Folder 80)
  - Evarts, John Jay
    - Correspondence, 1791-1833 (Box 58, Folder 81-85)
    - Essays, 1829-1832 (Box 59, Folder 86-89)
    - Journals, 1829-1832 (Box 59, Folder 90-93)
    - Lectures, 1831 (Box 59, Folder 94)
    - Lists, 1829-1832 (Box 59, Folder 95)
    - Notebooks, 1830-1833 (Box 59, Folder 96)
    - Poems, undated (Box 59, Folder 97)
    - School reports, 1827-1828 (Box 59, Folder 98)
  - Evarts, Martha
    - Correspondence
      - Evarts, Jeremiah, 1827-1831 (Box 59, Folder 99-100)
      - Evarts, John Jay, 1829-1832 (Box 59, Folder 101)
  - Evarts, William Maxwell: essay, 1834 (Box 59, Folder 102)
  - Unidentified, 1854-1862, undated (Box 59, Folder 103-104)
- Additional material, 1873-1881; Accession 2008-M-041
  This accession comprises family correspondence, primarily of William Maxwell Evarts to his son, Allen W. Evarts. Writings include the original manuscript reading copy of William Evarts' historic Centennial Oration in Philadelphia on July 4, 1876. This handwritten document is not in Evarts' hand but the corrections are by him.
  - Correspondence to Allen W. Evarts
    - Evarts, William M. (father), includes enclosed letter of George. B. Elkins, 1878-1881 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Evarts, Helen (mother), 1879 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Evarts, "Minnie" (sister), Circa 1873 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - "Lizzie" (aunt), 1877 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Writings
    - "Oration", 1876 July 4 (Box 1, Folder 5)